Jacob Kainen
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Jacob Kainen papers
1905-2003 (bulk 1940-2001)
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Jacob Kainen
17 linear feet
The Jacob Kainen papers measure 17 linear feet and date from 1905 to 2003 (bulk 1940-2001). The collection consists primarily of personal correspondence to and from friends and family members and professional correspondence concerning Kainen's activities as an artist, curator, teacher, and art collector. The collection also contains biographical material, writings, diaries, inventories, transcripts, printed material, photographs, works of art by other artists, and a videocassette.
Biographical Note
Jacob Kainen is remembered as painter, printmaker, teacher, curator, and collector. Born on December 7, 1909 in Waterbury, Connecticut, Kainen's family moved to New York City in 1918. Kainen studied at the Pratt Institute in Brooklyn from 1927 until 1930, and at the Art Student's League. In the early 1930s, Kainen became involved in social causes and formed close friendships with the early abstractionists, including John Graham, Ashile Gorky, and Stuart Davis. He joined the Artists' Union and became a contributor to its journal, Art Front, along with Stuart Davis and Harold Rosenberg. Jacob's participation in the Artists' Union was later investigated by the FBI.
From 1935 until 1942, Kainen worked for the Graphic Arts Division of the Works Progress Administration in New York City and began exhibiting with the New York School. It was during this period that he married Bertha Friedman. Jacob and Bertha had two sons together, Dan and Paul, and divorced in 1968. In 1942, Kainen made a life-changing decision to leave New York City and move to Washington, D.C. to accept what he thought would be a temporary position as a scientific aide in the Division of Graphic Arts at the Smithsonian Institution. Kainen became Assistant Curator and then Curator in 1946. He served as Curator for twenty years, completely reshaping the department and building the graphic arts collection. His print exhibitions brought the work of S.W. Hayter, Josef Albers, Adja Yunkers, Louis Lozowick, Karl Schrag, José Guerrero, Louis Schanker, Werner Drewes, and Boris Margo to Washington audiences - graphic work that might not have been shown that early in the area.
1947 marked the opening of the Washington Workshop Center for the Arts, where Kainen served as a teacher and guide to several important artists, helping to make the workshop a magnet for new talent and instrumental in furthering the careers of several artists. Although Kainen taught Gene Davis and Alma Thomas and introduced Morris Louis to Leon Berkowitz, he never considered himself a member of the "Washington Color School."
In 1949, the Corcoran Gallery of Art held a retrospective of Kainen's prints and three years later Kenneth Noland organized Kainen's first painting retrospective at Catholic University. Kainen's paintings from the 1940s illustrated a shift away from social realism toward abstract expressionism. In 1956, Jacob Kainen received a grant from the American Philosophical society to conduct research in Europe for his monograph on the English woodcut artist, John Baptist Jackson. He traveled to Europe again in 1962 to study paintings and prints from the Mannerist Period.
From 1966 until 1970, Kainen worked as the Curator of prints and drawings at the National Collection of Fine Arts (now the Smithsonian American Art Museum). He married Ruth Cole in February of 1969. Kainen retired from the Smithsonian a year later to devote himself full-time to his art, but continued to serve as a special consultant to the Smithsonian American Art Museum for nineteen years. In 1971 and 1972, Kainen taught painting and the history of printmaking at the University of Maryland. A retrospective of Kainen's paintings was held in 1993 at the National Museum of American Art (SAAM).
Throughout his artistic career, Kainen experimented with different mediums and explored different styles, yet he identified himself as a painter. Jacob Kainen participated in at least twenty-five one man shows and several group exhibitions. His works are in collections across the United States and abroad, including the National Gallery of Art, the Metropolitan Museum of Art, the Art Institute of Chicago, and the British Museum. He worked in his studio up until the time of his death on March 19, 2001 at his home in Chevy Chase, Maryland.
Scope and Content Note
The Jacob Kainen papers date from 1905 to 2003 (bulk 1940-2001), and measure 17 linear feet. The collection consists primarily of personal correspondence to and from friends and family members and professional correspondence concerning Kainen's activities as an artist, curator, teacher and art collector. The collection also contains biographical material, writings, diaries, inventories, transcripts, printed material, photographs, works of art by other artists, and a videocassette.
Biographical materials include items concerning Kainen's career as a curator and artist, in addition to a useful bibliography, detailed biographical outline, and a copy of an FBI report compiled on him. Correspondence/Subject files comprise the bulk of the collection and contain correspondence to and from both Jacob and Ruth Kainen's family members and friends concerning personal and professional matters. A historical as well as personal context for Jacob Kainen is established through his correspondence with several leading artists, critics, and curators of the time. The variety of correspondents within the series reflects Kainen's diverse experiences as an artist, teacher, curator, and collector. A substantial portion of the correspondence consists of letters specifically addressed to and written solely by Ruth Kainen.
Writings include materials written by and about Jacob Kainen. Kainen's formal and more scholarly articles and lectures are included with his short stories and poems dating from the 1930s through the 1990s. The series also includes several statements Kainen made regarding his artistic motivations and justifications. Dairies include both Jacob and Ruth Kainen's diary entries with Jacob Kainen's diaries dating mostly from the 1950s and 1960s and Ruth Kainen's entries covering more recent events from the 1970s though the 1990s. Also found are calendars, including daily calendars and travel itineraries from 1972 through 2001.
Transcripts of informal conversations with and formal interviews of Jacob Kainen constitute the next series and include interviews with reporters and critics, and conversations with friends and fellow artists. Many of the interviews and conversations contain comments from Ruth Kainen as well as Jacob Kainen. Also found are inventories of paintings by Jacob Kainen that were sold, missing, or unsold along with color photographs of some of Kainen's paintings. Printed materials include Kainen's exhibition catalogs and announcements, clippings of articles by and about Jacob Kainen, and an exhibition guestbook.
A substantial number of photographs are contained in the papers including those of Kainen with his family and friends, at exhibition openings, and working in his studios. Works of art by others includes handmade greeting cards, limited edition prints, and portfolios given to Jacob Kainen. The final item in the collection is a videocassette about the artist Martin Ries.
Arrangement
The Jacob Kainen papers are arranged into eleven series, according to type of material; materials within series are arranged alphabetically by name or subject and then chronologically.
Series 1: Biographical Material, 1939-1996, undated (Box 1; 13 folders)
Series 2: Correspondence/Subject Files, 1936-2003, undated (Boxes 1-10; 9.7 linear feet)
Series 3: Writings, 1939-2002, undated (Boxes 10-11; 0.6 linear feet)
Series 4: Diaries, 1952-2002, undated (Box 11; 0.5 linear feet)
Series 5: Calendars, 1972-2001 (Boxes 11-12; 0.6 linear feet)
Series 6: Transcripts, 1972-1994, undated (Boxes 12-13; 0.7 linear feet)
Series 7: Inventories, 1927-1999, undated (Box 13; 0.7 linear feet)
Series 8: Printed Material, 1939-2002, undated (Boxes 13-14, OV 18; 0.4 linear feet)
Series 9: Photographs, 1905-2000, undated (Boxes 14-16, OV 18; 2.6 linear feet)
Series 10: Works of Art by Others, 1944-2000, undated (Boxes 16-17, OV 18; 1 linear foot)
Series 11: Miscellany, 1999 (Box 17; 1 videocassette)
Related Material
The Archives of American Art contains a sound recording and microfilmed transcript of Avis Berman's interview with Jacob Kainen for the Archives of American Art's "Mark Rothko and His Times" oral history project (reel 4937). Microfilm copies of Bertha Kainen's correspondence from 1993 to 1994 regarding Avis Berman's essay about Jacob Kainen are also available at the Archives of American Art (reel 5030).
Separated Material
Materials loaned by Jacob and Ruth Kainen from 1973 to 1981 are available on microfilm reels 565, 2147-2149, and 2200. See Appendix A for an inventory of the contents of the microfilm reels.
Appendices
Appendix A: Inventory of Microfilm Reels
Reel 565, Frames 1-279:
Correspondence from 1939-1973, arranged alphabetically, beginning with Acheson and ending with Zigrosser, includes correspondence from Albert Christ-Janer, Clement Greenberg, and Joseph Solman.
Reel 565, Frames 280-388:
Clippings and exhibition catalogs from 1937-1973, arranged chronologically, includes exhibition catalogs for Jacob Kainen and other artists and a Washington Print Club Newsletter.
Reel 2147, Frames 1005-1302:
Correspondence from 1948-1979, arranged alphabetically, beginning with Miscellaneous A and ending with Colnaghi, P.D. & Co., Ltd., includes correspondence from Albert Christ-Janer and Michael Clark.
Reel 2148, Frames 2-1374:
Continuation of correspondence from Reel 2147 from 1941-1981, arranged alphabetically, beginning with Colnaghi, P.D. & Co., Ltd. and ending with Jerome Pollack, contains correspondence and some printed material from Creighton Gilbert, Norman Kent, and Tadeusz Lapinski.
Reel 2149, Frames 2-680:
Continuation of correspondence from Reel 2148 from 1944-1980, arranged alphabetically, beginning with Jerome Pollack and ending with Zeitlin & Ver Brugge Booksellers, contains correspondence and some printed material from Joseph Solman, Prentiss Taylor, Lynd Ward, and Angus Whyte.
Reel 2149, Frames 687-1073:
Writings by Jacob Kainen from 1937-1974, contains introductions for exhibition catalogs, articles about Gene Davis and Pop Art, encyclopedia entries, and some correspondence relating to Kainen's publications.
Reel 2200, Frames 881-911:
Correspondence and other papers relating to the Smithsonian Institution Loyalty Board's investigation of Jacob Kainen from 1942-1954, includes a letter written by J. Edgar Hoover. See Box 9, Smithsonian Institution Loyalty Board, for the original documents contained on this reel.
Appendix B: List of Miscellaneous Artists from Series 10
Arneson, Robert, undated
Aronson, Irene, 1962
Azechi, Umetaro, undated
Baskin, Leonard, undated
Beeri, Tuvia, 1978-1990
Brashow, James, undated
Browne, Rosalind Bengelsdorf, 1937
Bunts, Frank, undated
Butler, James, undated
Carcan, René, 1978-1990
Celan-Lestrange, Gisèle, 1977
Davis, Gene, 1969
Dayez, George, undated
Dean, Hilliard, 1980-1987, undated
De Léon, Ponce, 1965-1971, undated
Dos Santos, Bartolomeu, undated
Eichenberg, Fritz, 1977
Everson, William and Mary, 1948
Frasconi, Antonio, undated
Greenwald, Bernard, 1976
Griffith, Fuller, undated
Gubbiotti, Jason, 2000
Gumpert, Gunther, 1999
Gurr, Lena, 1971-1972, undated
Hashimoto, Okiie, undated
Highton, Anne, 1985-1991, undated
Isen, Hal and Anita, undated
Kent, Norman, 1966, undated
Kolin, Sasha, undated
Kreindler, Doris, 1967
Kurosaki, Akira, 1979
Landau, Jacob, 1971
Laughlin, Rebecca Mirsch, 1979
Leizman, William, 1961, undated
Lewis, Golda, 1955
Lothar, Ernest, 1951
Lyon, Rowland, undated
Margo, Boris, undated
Michel, Sally, 1970-1977
Moore, Benson, undated
Morse, Peter, 1973-1975
Music, Zoran, 1978
Nama, George A., 1965-1966
Neustadt, Barbara, 1971
Pearlstein, Philip, 1977-1978
Piza, 1983-1988
Purcell, Ann, 1997
Reed, Paul, 1969, undated
Refregier, Anton, 1971
Riabov, George, undated
Schwartz, Carl, undated
Smallwood, Michael, 1973
Stone, J., 1985
Solmon, Joseph, 1944-1952
Soyer, Raphael, undated
Sundberg, Alan, undated
Taylor, Prentiss, 1962-1963
Veinus, Abraham, 1989-1990
Viswanadhan, Velu, 1981
Ward, Lynd, undated
Weber, Joanne Goulart, 1977-1997
Wiley, William T., undated
White, Pat, 1972
Yoshida, undated
Yunkers, Adja, 1948
Index Terms
This collection is indexed in the online catalog of the Archives of American Art under the following index terms. People, families and organizations are listed under "Names" when they are creators or contributors and under "Subjects" when they are the topic of collection contents.
Subjects:
Gorky, Arshile, 1904-1948; Ries, Martin, 1926-
Subjects-Topical:
Painting, Abstract -- Washington (D.C.); Painting, Modern -- Washington (D.C.); Painters -- Washington (D.C.); Printmakers -- Washington (D.C.)
Types of Materials:
Diaries; Drawings; Transcripts; Photographs; Works of art; Videotapes
Names:
Lapinski, Tadeusz, 1928-; Greenwald, Bernard, 1908-1975; Hayter, Stanley William, 1901-; Berman, Avis; Broun, Elizabeth; Frohlich, Newton, 1936-; Griffiths, Antony; Rand, Harry; Reynolds, Jock; Addison Gallery of American Art; Baltimore Museum of Art; Corcoran Gallery of Art; National Gallery of Art (U.S.); Phillips Collection; Portland Art Museum (Or.); National Museum of American Art (U.S.)
Provenance
Correspondence, writings, and printed materials were lent to the Archives of American Art from 1973 to 1981 by Jacob and Ruth Kainen to be microfilmed and then returned after microfilming. Additional papers were donated to the Archives of American Art by Jacob and Ruth Kainen in several accessions from 1981 to 2000. Much of the original loaned materials were subsequently donated. Mrs. Ruth Kainen donated additional materials in 2003. On March 6, 2003 eight photographs of Jacob and Ruth Kainen were transferred from the National Portrait Gallery to the Archives of American Art.
Restrictions on Access
The collection is open for research. Microfilmed portion must be consulted on microfilm. Use of unmicrofilmed portion requires an appointment and is limited to the Washington, D.C. research facility.
Alternative Forms Available
The loaned materials are available on microfilm reels 565, 2147-2149, and 2200. The microfilm is available for interlibrary loan.
Series Descriptions/Container Listing
- Biographical Material, 1939-1996, undated, Series 1:; (Box 1; 13 folders)
  The series includes applications, position descriptions, résumés, and a copy of the FBI report compiled on Kainen. Also contained are birth certificates, passports, biographical outlines, bibliographies, and lists of works by Jacob Kainen. The series is arranged alphabetically by type of material and subject and chronologically under each heading.
  - Applications and Forms, 1964-1967, undated (Box 1)
  - Biographical Documents, 1969-1996 (Box 1)
  - Biographical Outlines, 1975-1991, undated (Box 1)
  - Exhibition Information undated (Box 1)
  - FBI Report, 1948-1955, (5 folders) (Box 1)
  - Painting Information, undated (Box 1)
  - Position Descriptions, 1961, undated (Box 1)
  - Résumés, 1939-1989, undated (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous, 1939-1978, undated (Box 1)
- Correspondence/Subject Files, 1936-2003, undated, Series 2:; (Boxes 1-10; 9.7 linear feet)
  The series includes personal and professional correspondence to and from family members, friends, scholars, artists, curators, and students. There is a significant amount of material dealing with exhibitions, donations, gifts, and appraisals of items from Kainen's art collection. Some notable correspondents include Clement Greenberg, Stuart Davis, and S.W. Hayter. A substantial amount of correspondence was written and received exclusively by Ruth Cole Kainen. The series contains some photographs, printed material, and handmade cards. The correspondence files and subject files were combined into one series as in the original arrangement by the Kainen's. In most cases, the correspondence was originally arranged alphabetically by the correspondent's name, but there were a few files included in the original series that were filed by subject and contained correspondence relating to a specific topic or event. Correspondents with fewer than five letters are filed alphabetically in miscellaneous folders.
  - Unidentifiable and Illegible, 1963-2000, undated (Box 1)
  - Abbeville Press, 1984 (Box 1)
  - Achenback Foundation for Graphic Arts, 1974-1989, undated (Box 1)
  - Ackland Art Museum: see Millard, Charles W. (Box 1)
  - Acton, David, 1988-1997, undated, (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Adas Israel Congregation, 1997-2002 (Box 1)
  - Addison Gallery of American Art (see also Reynolds, Jock), 1990-2002, (5 folders) (Box 1)
  - Agee, William, 1992-2001, undated, (3 folders) (Box 1)
  - Allen, Darick, 1989-1998 (Box 1)
  - Allen, Jane Addams, 1983-1990 (Box 1)
  - Allentuck, Marcia Epstein, 1986-1999 (Box 1)
  - Amen, Irving (contains handmade card), 1957-1991 (Box 1)
  - American Academy and Institute of Arts and Letters, 1992 (Box 1)
  - Annex Galleries, 1990-1996 (Box 1)
  - Appraisals, 1967-1980, undated, (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Arnold, William N., 1979-1987 (Box 1)
  - Arosemena, Justo, 1958-1995 (Box 1)
  - Art in America, 1978-1995 (Box 1)
  - Art Institute of Chicago (see also Joachim, Harold), 1982-1999 (Box 1)
  - Art in the Embassies, 1970-1985, undated, (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Art News, 1974-1995 (Box 1)
  - Art Supply Inventories, 1974-1992, undated, (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Art Supply Sources, 1972-1982, undated, (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Australian National Gallery, 1985-1989, undated, (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Avery, Sally, 1975-1994, undated (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous A: Abrams-Anyos, 1969-1999 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous A: Ari-Award in the Visual Arts, 1978-1998, undated (Box 1)
  - Bachman, Gertrude, 1977-1980 (Box 1)
  - Bain, Iain, 1979-1982 (Box 1)
  - Baltimore Museum of Art (see also Carlson, Victor), 1948-2003, undated, (7 folders) (Box 1)
  - Baro, Gene (see also Brooklyn Museum), 1974-1982 (Box 1)
  - Baumgartner Galleries, 1984-1987, undated (Box 1)
  - Bayley Art Museum, 1999-2001, undated (Box 1)
  - Bedford Books, 1995-1996 (Box 1)
  - Bergen, D. Thomas, 1986-1988 (Box 1)
  - Berkman, Lillian, 1970-2000, undated (Box 1)
  - Berman, Avis, 1980-2002, undated, (11 folders) (Box 1)
  - Berry, Max N. and Heidi L., 1992-2001 (Box 1)
  - Berry, Timothy, 1976-1994 (Box 1)
  - Bindman, David 1990-2003, undated (Box 1)
  - Black, Peter, 1991-1992, undated (Box 2)
  - Blitz, Nelson and Catherine, 1986-1991 (Box 2)
  - Bloom, Max and Pearl, 1980-1994, undated (Box 2)
  - Brie, Roxanne, 1977-1999, undated (Box 2)
  - British Museum (see also Griffiths, Antony V.), 1984-2002, (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - Brooklyn Museum, 1974-1999, (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - Broun, Elizabeth (see also Smithsonian American Art Museum), 1984-2001, undated, (5 folders) (Box 2)
  - Bullard, John, 1975-1989 (Box 2)
  - Butler, Bryce, 1957-2001, undated, (12 folders) (Box 2)
  - Butler, Elizabeth C., 1974-2000, undated, (3 folders) (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous B: Badgley-Bealle, 1947-2002, undated (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous B: Beaumont-Braude, 1950-1997, undated (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous B: Brennan-Burton, 1976-2001, undated (Box 2)
  - Campbell, Lawrence, 1983-1985, undated (Box 2)
  - Carey, Frances, 1981-2000, undated, (4 folders) (Box 2)
  - Carlson, Victor, 1977-1989 (Box 2)
  - Carmean, E.A., Jr., 1984-1995, undated (Box 2)
  - Cate, Phillip Dennis, 1974-1991 (Box 2)
  - Chambers, Joy, 1993-1999, undated (Box 2)
  - Charles Brand Machinery Inc., 1968-1987, undated (Box 2)
  - Childs, Bernard and Judith (contains handmade card), 1966-2002 (Box 2)
  - Clark, Michael, 1974-2001, undated (Box 2)
  - Cleveland Center for Contemporary Art: see New Gallery of Contemporary Art (Box 2)
  - Cole, Mr. and Mrs. Paul, 1983, undated (Box 2)
  - Cole, Phoebe, 1961-2001, undated, (5 folders) (Box 2)
  - Cole, Sylvan, 1967-1997 (Box 2)
  - Cole, Teden, 1973-1974, undated (Box 2)
  - Columbia Festival of the Arts, 1996, undated (Box 2)
  - Condolences, 2001, undated, (5 folders) (Box 2)
  - Conroy, Sarah Booth, 1970-2000 (Box 3)
  - Cooper-Hewitt, National Design Museum, 1978-1991, undated (Box 3)
  - Corcoran Gallery of Art (see also Levy, David), 1949-2001, undated, (9 folders) (Box 3)
  - Cowart, Jack (see also National Gallery of Art), 1988-1997 (Box 3)
  - Cyril, Ruth, 1955-1974, undated (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous C: Cabral-Christie's, 1948-1997, undated (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous C: Cincinnati-Conisbee, 1973-2001, undated (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous C: Conroy-Current Biography, 1977-1996, undated (Box 3)
  - Davidson Galleries, 1988, undated (Box 3)
  - Davis, Mr. and Mrs. Gene, 1966-1988, undated, (2 folders) (Box 3)
  - Dean, Charles R., 2000-2002 (Box 3)
  - Dean, Hilliard, 1977-1999, undated, (2 folders) (Box 3)
  - Delgado-Restrepo, Gloria, 1977-1981 (Box 3)
  - Dickerson Combination Press, 1977-1987, undated (Box 3)
  - Dineen, Tom, 1974-1988, undated (Box 3)
  - Disney, Jean, 1963-1985 (Box 3)
  - Donovan, Bobby, 1981-2002, undated (Box 3)
  - Drewes, Werner and Maria, 1969-2000, undated (Box 3)
  - Driskell, David C., 1983-2002 (Box 3)
  - Drysdale, Nancy, 1991-1999 (Box 3)
  - Dube, Dr. Wolf-Dieter, 1981-1990 (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous D: Da Capo Press-Day, 1964-2002 (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous D: DeAngelis-Dixon, 1972-2000, undated (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous D: Dolan-Dyke, 1953-1999, undated (Box 3)
  - Eichenberg, Fritz, 1963-1977 (Box 3)
  - Elkins, William and Connie, 1983-2003 (Box 3)
  - Elz, Ingeborg, 1986-1993, undated (Box 3)
  - Epstein, Sarah (Sally) G., 1976-1994 (Box 3)
  - Equitable Gallery, 1993-1994, undated (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous E: Early-Evergood, 1940-2002, undated (Box 3)
  - Farmer, Jane M., 1978-1991 (Box 3)
  - Federal Bureau of Investigation, 1992-1996, undated (Box 3)
  - Fern, Alan and Lois, 1982-2000 (Box 3)
  - Fernandez, Tomas J., 1979-1992, undated (Box 3)
  - Ferry, Carmen, 1973-1988, undated (Box 3)
  - Field, Richard S., 1972-2000, undated, (4 folders) (Box 3)
  - Fielding, Mrs. A.W., 1975-1981 (Box 3)
  - Fine, Ruth, 1973-2002, undated, (2 folders) (Box 3)
  - Firestone, Susan, 1983-1991, undated (Box 3)
  - Fitzpatrick, James F. and Sandra, 1988-2000 (Box 3)
  - Fleming, Lee, 1988-1999, undated (Box 3)
  - Flint, Janet (see also Hirschl & Alder Galleries, Inc.), 1972-1997, undated (Box 3)
  - Fogg Art Museum, 1979-1998 (Box 3)
  - Fontaine, John Clovis and Elizabeth E., 1994-2001, undated (Box 3)
  - Forgey, Mr. Benjamin, 1975-1995 (Box 3)
  - Fort Wayne Museum of Art, 1994-2000, undated, (3 folders) (Box 3)
  - Fort Worth Art Museum: see Carmean, E.A., Jr. (Box 3)
  - Foucheux, Rick, 1997-2000, undated (Box 3)
  - Frampton, George T. and Betsy K., 1989-2001, undated (Box 3)
  - Franz Bader, Inc., 1965-1993, undated (Box 3)
  - French, Elisabeth, 1970-2002, undated (Box 3)
  - Friedman, Herman P., 1974-1994, undated (Box 3)
  - Friedman, Sylvia, 1966-1995, undated (Box 3)
  - Frohlich, Newton, 1966-1995, (5 folders) (Box 3)
  - Fuller, Martin B. 1944-1968, undated (Box 3)
  - Fund for Democracy and Development, 1992, undated (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous F: Farber-Flynn, 1969-2002, undated (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous F: Folger-Fuchs, 1956-1997, undated (Box 4)
  - Garner, Keith and Constance, 1962-1966 (Box 4)
  - General Services Administration, 1988-1990 (Box 4)
  - Georgetown University, 1985-2002, undated (Box 4)
  - George Washington University, 1944-1994 (Box 4)
  - Gibson, Eric, 1990-1998, undated (Box 4)
  - Gichner, Lawrence E., 1983-1990 (Box 4)
  - Gilbert, Dr. Creighton, 1973-1978 (Box 4)